# Dilek Baykara

🔀 baykara.d@gmail.com 🛛 Brooklyn, New York 📞 862 • 219 • 9591 🗼 https://dilekdeveloper.com

https://github.com/dilekbaykara in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dilekbaykara/

## Summary

Full-stack web developer delivering solutions with a customer-first approach by utilizing front-end technologies to prioritize user experience while supporting business metrics. Experienced graphic designer leveraging software development process to ensure the design supports the function of the website.

## Work Experience

### Freelance Web Developer

2023 - Present

- Built a web crawler that solves a problem for birders that use the eBird mobile app
- eBird App web crawler iterates through bird watching sessions and displays information on a map for birders to review and keep a record of each birding session.
- eBird App was built with Node.js, Typescript, Puppeteer, Leaflet.js, HTML, and CSS
- Worked on optimizing code in order to ensure results are displayed in an efficient manner.

Robert Graham 2021 - Present

Associate Graphic Designer

- Created best selling graphics/artworks for Robert Graham mainline knits / wovens
- Initiated the use of DALL E 2 for creating artwork for the design team.
- Solved and prevented copyright issues when purchasing artwork from studios.
- Assigned tasks to freelancers to distribute workload in order to meet deadlines

#### Freelance Illustrator

2013 - Present

Client list includes:

- Scientific American
  Fast Company
  Rhino Entertainment (Grateful Dead)
- AARP Magazine
  The New Republic
  Bust Magazine
  The Boston Globe
- The Intercept Car and Driver

## Skills

Javascript / Typescript / HTML / CSS / SQL /React / React Native / Node.js / Jest Next.js / Puppeteer / VSCode / npm / webpack / Git / Express / Figma Adobe Photoshop / Adobe Illustrator / Adobe After Effects / drawing / painting

## Education

Computer Science, Programming with a Purpose

2023

Coursera, Princeton University

School of Visual Arts, New York, NY

2013